kind of put on reading lists for
undergraduate courses in the States,
which is like, you know, if you're
a writer, that's kind of like, you
know, that's the kind of Holy Grail
is kind of getting your book put on
the undergraduate reading list for
courses in the United States because
you sell lots of copies. And it's
been in print since the 1930s.
And one of the points that they make
in this book is that when you're
reading a book, you don't have to
start at the beginning and go all the
way through to the end. You can read
bits from the middle. You can read
bits from the middle. You can look
at the table of contents, you can
kind of pick chapters that you think
are interesting, and you can read
the conclusion first. Even with kind
of mystery stories and stuff, some
people read the conclusion first
before they read the rest of the book.
I don't do that, but people
do. Even with fiction,
for example, one of the suggestions
with War and Peace is that you read
the war bits and leave the peace bits
out because the war bits are more
interesting.
So kind of like, there are lots of
different ways of reading a book. And
then I had this kind of like forehead
slapping realisation. There we go.
That's start.
I had this forehead
slapping realisation.
That, oh yeah, it's the same for
writing. You can do the same for
writing. You don't have to start the
beginning and go through with the
end. You can start in the middle.
You can start with kind of like the
high level structure or you can
start in the detail. You can start in
lots and lots of different places.
and um so kind of like this was kind
of a realisation for me it's one of
these things like be careful on my
glasses but it's like a it's like a
forehead slapping realisation oh my
god i had again i had this naive
idea that the way you write a book is
like you start the beginning and
you go through to the end and um you
don't